

MOUHAMMADOU OURY DIALLO

Dakar, Senegal | +221762714888 | <u>ryhow99@gmail.com</u>

<u>LinkedIn:</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/mouhammadouod/ <u>Portfolio:</u> https://my-portfolio-two-steel-20.vercel.app/

Github: https://github.com/MouhammadouOD

SUMMARY

Talented software development professional with over 4 years of experience in Full Stack Development. Consistent in delivering clean, error-free, reliable code to meet current or expected needs. Well-versed in software trends and confident in multiple languages, frameworks and programming tools.

EXPÉRIENCE

LuciSun (Sart-Dames-Avelines, Wallonia, Belgique)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER | March2023 - Present 2024 (Remote)

- Working with the team for building LuciSun's products
- Tech-Stack: Next JS- Tailwind CSS SQLite Fast API Python

CECA - Audit & Conseil (Dakar, SN)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER | November 2023 - January 2024 (Remote)

- As lead designer and developer, I led the creation of a revolutionary custom application for internal management within an accounting firm.
- Thanks to this application, each employee benefits from a personalized and secure experience, logging in with unique identifiers.
- The application, which I developed in its entirety, offers a customizable solution that adapts to the firm's specific needs, adding exceptional flexibility to day-to-day operations.
- Tech-Stack: React JS- TailwindCSS MongoDB NestJs

PI-Horaire

FULL STACK DEVELOPER | July 2023 - August 2023 (Freelance)

- Worked as a pair to build A Machine Scheduling App used in industry.
- Tech-Stack: NextJs TailwindCSS Prisma SQL Server Redux TLK NestJs

SENDIGITAL (Dakar - SN)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER | April 2023 - May 2023 (Freelance)

- Build A SaaS to create digital Vcard with Qrcode.
- Tech-Stack: NextJs TailwindCSS Prisma MongoDB Redux TLK
- Contact The App Owner: Email: <u>benilayegueye@gmail.com</u> Call: +221 77 381 33 34

OMEDEMA (Paris - France)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER | SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT (REMOTE)

- Worked on Omedema's Landing Page
- Created UI Components
- Coded the landing Page using NextJS, TailwindCss, TypeScript, NodeJS
- Performed Unit tests for all components using Jest, react-testing-library, Enzyme
- Wrote integration tests with Jest and Enzyme
- Worked on Omedema's Platform-app Web App
- Built forms for signing in the platform with react-hook-forms
- Built the entire live-chat using Socket-io to put in place the real-time chat feature
- Setup the State management feature for the app with Redux-toolkit.
- Setup api for updloading file on the portfolio section
- Build the UI for portfolio section with modals
- Responsible of the CI/CD pipeline
- Worked on Platform migration

GOMYCODE (Dakar - SN)

FULL STACK JS INSTRUCTOR | JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

- Support the students in their learning
- Developed guides and course materials focused on helping students learn
- Built and maintained positive relationships with students to facilitate positive and effective educational experiences
- Evaluated students progress
- Performed WorkShops

SEN IT TECHNOLOGIE (Dakar - SN)

FULL STACK MERN DEVELOPER | JUNE 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Built an inventory and Sales Management Application with the MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, NodeJS) and Bootstrap
- Project analysis
- Redacted functional and non-functional requirements
- Built Class, Use case and Sequence Diagrams
- Designed and Implemented the app using MERN Stack

REGIONAL HOSPITAL OF OUROSSOGUI (Matam - SN)

FULL STACK JAVA DEVELOPER | JUNE 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020 (REMOTE)

- Designed a Hospital Management app for patients and medical records monitoring
- Built Beans classes (User, Appointment, Medicine, PatientsRecord, Consultation)
- Implemented DAO classes for all Beans
- Wrote sql database script to setup all tables and fill in default informations
- Built servlets for every JSP(Java Server Pages)
- Built JSP for every page of the application

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- ReactJS
- NextJS
- TailwindCss | Chadcn
- TypeScript
- NodeJS
- ExpressJS | NestJs
- MongoDB | Postgresql
- Prisma | Mongoose | Sequelize
- Java, JavaEE, JSP, MVC
- MySQL

- Cloud Development (AWS)
- Infrastructure As Code (CloudFormation)
- CI/CD pipeline (Circle CI, Ansible, Prometheus)
- Microservices at Scale using AWS & Kubernetes(FaaS, AWS Lambda, Cloud9, Docker)
- Design Patterns
- SCRUM

EDUCATION

August 2022 Bachelor's degree | Software Engineering

École Supérieure Polytechnique de Dakar - Dakar, DK

- Software Process Engineering (Scheduled Processes, Agile Processes, SCRUM Methodology)
- Advanced DBMS (SQL, Transactions, Distributed DB, DB Management with ORACLE & MYSQL)
- XML, ES6, NodeJS, ExpressJs, MongoDB
- Design Pattern with Java (Factory-Method, Singleton)
- UML
- Algorithms
- Security Technologies, Cryptography (Encryption, Symmetrical and Asymmetrical Algorithms, Certificates, Metasploit)
- Project Management
- C language
- Network Administration (SSH, DNS, DHCP, FTP, TFTP, SMTP)
- Operating Systems (Mono-programming, Multi programming, Interruptions, Context Switching, Process Scheduling, Memory Management)
- Operational Research Linear programming (Graphic & Simplex Methodologies)

University Diploma of Technology | Computer Engineering

École Supérieure Polytechnique de Dakar – Dakar, DK

- A two year of intense learning
- Algorithms, Mathematics, Network Administration
- System Administration with Linux
- Database Administration with MySQL, ORACLE and PL/SQL
- Programming Language HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C, Java, JavaEE
- Communication

2017 Baccalauréat | S1 (Mathematics & Physics Specialities)

Lycée Seydina LimamouLaye – Dakar, DK

CERTIFICATIONS

- FULLSTACK MERN | GOMYCODE 2021 <u>click here to view</u>
- CLOUD DEVOPS ENGINEER | UDACITY 2023

LANGUAGES

- Wolof First Language
- French Proficient
- English B1
- Arabic Elementary